<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">The amalgamation of semi-useful information</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io/" />
<updated>2015-12-03T16:58:34-06:00</updated>
<id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//</id>
<author>
  <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
  <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//</uri>
  <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's the thing about Millennials]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/heres-the-thing-about-millennials/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/heres-the-thing-about-millennials</id>
  <published>2015-12-03T08:59:55-06:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-03T08:59:55-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;when-you-google-millennials-here-are-a-few-of-the-top-search-results&quot;&gt;When you google “Millennials,” here are a few of the top search results:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Millennials - Wikipedia: Millennials (also known as the Millennial Generation or Generation Y) are the demographic cohort following Generation X. There are no precise dates when the generation starts and ends; most researchers and commentators use birth years ranging from the early 1980s to the early 2000s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “Millennials” Are Coming - CBS News&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do Millennials Make for Bad Employees? - The Atlantic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Millennials Gettng Help From Parents - The Atlantic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Recession Generation - Forbes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-you-look-at-word-clouds-associated-with-millennials-common-keywords-include&quot;&gt;When you look at “Word Clouds” associated with Millennials, common keywords include:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gadgets/Technology/Smart Devices/Internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underemployed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Impulsive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instant Gratification&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savvy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These keywords can have both negative and positive connotations depending on the audience. From what I’ve seen, most articles written by “Non-Millennials” originate from two schools of thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tenacious, social, inclusive, ambitious, educated, creative, etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lazy, entitled, too politically correct, hippies, disrespectful, highly opinionated, irresponsible with money, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fine-whatever&quot;&gt;Fine. Whatever.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the day, I exhibit all these qualities. For the most part, I can deal with these characterizations. All things considered, the one thing that we are particularly bad at is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sitting-still&quot;&gt;Sitting Still.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask us to “be patient,” or “wait for someone else,” it drives us insane. When we see a problem, whether it be a bug in someone’s code, or an inefficiency in a queue, or inaction in a workplace hierarchy, we want to fix it. The more we are asked to wait, and the longer it takes for us to get our hands on the problem, the faster we move from the 1st school of thought to the 2nd one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials, and every generation ahead of us, are more likely to throw caution to the wind to solve problems. We are more likely to step up to call out the problems in our society - whether it be on campus, in the work place, or on capitol hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are action driven &amp;amp; solution driven, and sometimes that gets us into trouble. Because a lot of times, we forget that there are situations in which we have to ask for permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;could-we-be-viewed-as-being-disrespectful-impulsive-and-doing-other-peoples-jobs-yes&quot;&gt;Could we be viewed as being “disrespectful,” “impulsive” and “doing other people’s jobs?” Yes.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s our nature. We grew up on the instant gratification of technology. We grew up in schools that encouraged us to be “well rounded,” and “jacks of all trades.” If you think we are just going to sit still, and let problems continue to happen, you have another thing coming. We really don’t like waiting around for someone to come up with a solution, or for issues to “go away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will throw the hierarchy out the window if it means getting the job done, and the success of the team. We will rewrite your code, or our team’s report if it sucks. We will start a conversation on campus about societal racism. We will redesign your logo, website, campaign, wardrobe, or even Point of View if it isn’t current. We will call politicians out for their hypocrisy, regardless of what party they are associated with. We will force large tech companies to address gendered double standards. We will work around the clock to solve problems, and bring change to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-do-it-with-technology-with-fierceness-and-with-the-hashtag-sorrynotsorry&quot;&gt;We’ll do it with technology, with fierceness, and with the hashtag #SorryNotSorry.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Quit comparing us to the “Next Generation”/”Gen Z”/Whatever. We are all more or less cut from the same cloth, and they are basically our younger siblings/younger cousins.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/heres-the-thing-about-millennials/&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s the thing about Millennials&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on December 03, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[It still hurts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/it-still-hurts/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/it-still-hurts</id>
  <published>2015-11-17T12:32:55-06:00</published>
  <updated>2015-11-17T12:32:55-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Self doubt is a tricky constraint. Growing up, my experiences taught me that I could tackle anything &amp;amp; everything I set my mind to. My pre-college &amp;amp; college experience taught me otherwise. But that’s a story for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduating into the workforce has allowed me to unlock parts of the straight jacket of self doubt. In most cases, with a bit of hard work, and tenacity, I have been able to tackle some pretty sizable problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;however&quot;&gt;However…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with, and being continuously surrounded with smart people keeps me in the jacket. Some people claim that I’m just as smart &amp;amp; capable as everyone else, but it is hard for me to convince myself that this is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sometimes-i-can&quot;&gt;Sometimes I can.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten better at it, and I have gotten better at prolonging my time out of the jacket. Without being as plagued by self doubt. The absolute worst thing you can do is to remind me that the straight jacket exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-really-want-to-hurt-me&quot;&gt;Do you really want to hurt me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convince me to doubt myself. And I’ll take care of the rest for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll beat myself into a pulp and lock myself up in the straight jacket.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/it-still-hurts/&quot;&gt;It still hurts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on November 17, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things We Learned in Nashville]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/things-we-learned-in-nashville/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/things-we-learned-in-nashville</id>
  <published>2015-10-28T14:39:55-05:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-28T14:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>aditi.rajagopal92@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;this-post-was-co-written--edited-by-kendall-nelson&quot;&gt;This post was co-written &amp;amp; edited by Kendall Nelson&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, we attended the Society of Women Engineers Annual Conference (we15) in Nashville Tennessee. We stayed at a hostel in Downtown Nashville, 
walked around everywhere, and were continually inspired by the people we met. In addition to learning about ourselves, the society, and the state of female engineers everywhere, we learned these key facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cowboy boots are expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “easiest” way to get cowboy boots is to convince your friends to opt into the “buy 1 get 2 free” deal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;St. Louis BBQ Sauce is our favorite (sorry Tennessee)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chocolate Chip Cookie Ice Cream Cones are better in theory than in practice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creepy dudes down South at least know how to dance nicely (their footwork is impeccable, you don’t even need to try)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being surrounded by 8000+ female engineers is like being surrounded by 8000+ of your long distance besties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always carry your manager’s business card (in addition to many of your own) - you never know when you’ll need it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never be afraid to hug inspirational people. Chances are, their inspirational qualities will rub off :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a lot of “problems” that need to be solved with respect to Women in Engineering &amp;amp; Women in Technology. Creating dichotomies is not what STEM fields need right now….&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to life chats with as many people as possible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you haven’t already, read up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/thecut/2013/05/shine-theory-how-to-stop-female-competition.html&quot;&gt;Shine Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hope-to-see-yall-at-we16-in-philadelphia&quot;&gt;Hope to see y’all at we16 in Philadelphia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout some more highlights via our compiled Storify:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville/embed?header=false&amp;amp;border=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville.js?header=false&amp;amp;border=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;#we15 - Nashville TN&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=======&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;check-out-our-storify&quot;&gt;Check out our Storify!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Hope to see y’all at we16 in Philadelphia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville/embed?border=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville.js?border=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/Aditi_Rajagopal/we15-nashville&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;#we15 - Nashville TN&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/things-we-learned-in-nashville/&quot;&gt;Things We Learned in Nashville&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on October 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quick Update]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/sorry-not-sorry/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/sorry-not-sorry</id>
  <published>2015-09-01T14:39:55-05:00</published>
  <updated>2015-09-01T14:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Revamping this website was on my “To-Do” list for almost a year before I actually scrapped it. Overcommitting and my lack of creative confidence puts me in a vortex of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side/Optional projects get hit the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a detail oriented perfectionist. So when it comes to these types of projects, if I’m not 100% happy, it’s easy for me to scrap it and forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what happened to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-tuned&quot;&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/sorry-not-sorry/&quot;&gt;A Quick Update&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on September 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Year in review]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/a-year-in-review/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/a-year-in-review</id>
  <published>2015-09-01T14:39:55-05:00</published>
  <updated>2015-09-01T14:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s midnight on November 5th 2015, and I’m staring at blank screen at www.hemingwayapp.com. My creative confidence is pretty low, and the day-light-savings continues to riddle my performance. I doubt that a cup of coffee is going to boost anything. All I want to do is sleep…and hope that this post writes itself. But here we are. Let me tell you my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rewind-back-to-fall-term-2013&quot;&gt;Rewind back to fall term 2013.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s midterm season and I’m a senior at University of Michigan. The ultimate goal is two-fold: graduate &amp;amp; land a full-time job. I applied to every company I could, and I was neck deep in work and extra curriculars. I interviewed with Jake Morlock (who is now my 2nd line manager) on October 11th 2013. After a 45 minute interview, I knew there was something special about him, and his team. Rochester Minnesota? Never heard of it. Doesn’t matter. Compared to all the other recruiters I had met, there was a distinct “IBM Difference” that felt right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;people-always-saygo-with-your-gut&quot;&gt;People always say…“Go with your gut.”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received my offer from IBM’s OpenStack Development team on October 29th 2013. I accepted the offer on November 21st 2013. Reading through my email archives is so unreal. I can’t believe it’s been 2 years already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ultimate-goal-achieved&quot;&gt;2/2 - Ultimate Goal Achieved.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated from University of Michigan College of Engineering on May 4th 2014. My best friend and I split a can of red-bull before heading to commencement because we stayed up all night. In spite of all the trials and tribulations, we made it. Looking back on it, I can’t fathom how we did it; I’m just thankful that we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after, I was on my way to India to volunteer with my SWE Collegiate section in Walchandnagar India. For 1 week, we hosted a 1 week STEM camp for 6-10th graders. The following week, we toured India’s Golden Triangle (Jaipur, Agra &amp;amp; Dehli). It was an amazing experience. I hope to relive it’s essence through IBM’s Corporate Service Corps program.
Remember Rochester, Minnesota?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my first visit to IBM’s site in Rochester Minnesota on July 11th 2014. I remember sobbing the entire the drive from the Minneapolis-St. Paul airport to Rochester. My worst nightmare felt like it was coming true - I was moving to the middle of nowhere. But I got to meet Jake again; and I got to experience “Minnesota Nice” for the first time.  It was a bit reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of July was a blur. Somehow, I ended up with a nice apartment, car, furniture, and a pretty slick ID lanyard. I started orientation on August 4th 2014 in Research Triangle Park (RTP), North Carolina. Peak summer and peak humidity. Unfortunately, I did not meet any IBMers who were going to be working in Rochester with me. Armed with my ThinkPad and my freshly minted IBM ID badge, I walked into the IBM Rochester Office on August 6th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-was-a-pleasant-surprise---not-the-nightmare-i-had-thought&quot;&gt;It was a pleasant surprise - not the nightmare I had thought&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t happen over night, but I found myself surrounded by some pretty amazing people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He always scoffs when I say this to him, but I have the best office-mate a girl could have
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/officemate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OfficeMate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was on a team with two other new hires - both of which are smarter than me, but are willing to help me learn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have an incredible first-line manager who finds me opportunities (like this one) to exercise my creative skills. She is also supportive of my personal interests, and pushes me technically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a large team of mentors ranging from age, experience, role, and business unit within IBM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a group of wonderful friends at IBM who believe in me, and look out for me in their own unique ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-tuned&quot;&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/a-year-in-review/&quot;&gt;A Year in review&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on September 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look! It's Finally Live!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/hello-world/" />
  <id>http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/hello-world</id>
  <published>2015-07-16T14:39:55-05:00</published>
  <updated>2015-07-16T14:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Aditi Rajagopal</name>
    <uri>http://aditirajagopal.github.io/</uri>
    <email>araja@umich.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;After quite a lot of thought, drafting, procrastination, coding, and coffee, I’m pleased to announce/show/display my new website &amp;amp; blog! This could not have been done without the help of my family, friends, new hires, and interns - it’s always good to have people making sure you are being accountable….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to go to work now so…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-tuned&quot;&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io//blog/hello-world/&quot;&gt;Look! It&#39;s Finally Live!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Aditi Rajagopal at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aditirajagopal.github.io/&quot;&gt;The amalgamation of semi-useful information&lt;/a&gt; on July 16, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>